So the sample on this is [__] really
cool and powerful.
In the background of the song, pretty
subtly, but once you hear it, you can't
unhear, at least I can't, but there's a
literal work song. It's called Early in
the Morning, recorded in 1948.
>> [music]
>> It was sung by four incarcerated black
men in Mississippi Penitentiary who were
forced to work on these, essentially an
extension of slavery and they have
forced prison labor.
>> You found that? Oh, that's sick. Okay. I
used that because I knew like, oh, this
makes sense. This is like closer to like
my roots or what I'll be talking about.
It's like the slavery stuff, the prison
to school to pipeline. And yeah, I just
thought the essence, even if you didn't
hear it all the way, you could kind of
feel it, you know what I'm saying? I
also like how it ties into the theme of
the album because you have these men in
this really ugly situation and creating
beauty.